[{"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8c0", "question": "From which country did the smorgasbord originate?", "answer": "Sweden", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339081", "question": "Who wrote \"Born Free\", \"Living Free\" and \"Forever Free\"?", "answer": "Joy Adamson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd667a0a5bfecdd737e086b", "question": "What condition is singultus better known as?", "answer": "Hiccups", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2f9", "question": "Over what ocean did Amelia Earhart disappear?", "answer": "The Pacific", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6008dd25f4f3bc4a292f861e", "question": "Mother Teresa received the Nobel Peace Prize for what?", "answer": "Peace, or more accurately \"for work undertaken in the struggle to overcome poverty and distress, which also constitutes a threat to peace\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b618", "question": "What would you find in a bento box?", "answer": "Food", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d1193d4fea7fe947a2228c", "question": "Which song from the \"White Album\" was originally titled \"Maharishi\"?", "answer": "Sexy Sadie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "594d06931a1c922dd1ac64ad", "question": "Who devised a method for classifying fingerprints?", "answer": "Francis Galton", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5901d8bd709c1c34536e6ea6", "question": "In what country was the first coin operated slot machine invented?", "answer": "US", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59774433284458f1d785442e", "question": "The original name of New York City was what?", "answer": "New Amsterdam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a3c", "question": "What type of musical instrument is crafted with two parallel pipes, one known as a chanter and the other a drone?", "answer": "The bagpipe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a858", "question": "Which river does the Brooklyn Bridge cross?", "answer": "East River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fede4a26ce05a3942286ddf", "question": "In 1994, Elton John wrote the songs for which Disney animated film with lyricist Tim Rice?", "answer": "\"The Lion King\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "60077fb4bd51d85e222ab63f", "question": "What painter was summoned to Rome in 1481 to decorate the walls of the Sistine Chapel?", "answer": "Sandro Botticelli was summoned to Rome in 1481 by Pope Sixtus IV, and charged with decorating the walls of the Sistine Chapel.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600cc3d06de0eb824d4052ee", "question": "If one is wearing a swimsuit in Florida in public, what is illegal for one to do?", "answer": "Sing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bd4", "question": "Who is often credited with breaking hip hop into mainstream music?", "answer": "Run D.M.C.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea7dc8ff048f679a45abfe", "question": "Androphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Men", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60136f891381754895396378", "question": "What superhero uses a device called \"The Cosmic Treadmill\"?", "answer": "Flash -- The Cosmic Treadmill is used to help the Flash amplify his already considerable powers.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b077", "question": "What was the last name of Civil Rights activist Malcolm X?", "answer": "Little", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58b8d6f32b42d4a3561a9f09", "question": "What country is Dinish Island a part of?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c23a", "question": "What do Vanilla Ice, Willow Smith, Rob Schneider, John Candy and Michael Landon all have in common?", "answer": "They were all born on Halloween", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b41a", "question": "Which Empire was Cambodia once known as?", "answer": "Khmer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd90", "question": "Who was the first coach of the Green Bay Packers?", "answer": "Curly Lambeau", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388fb", "question": "What is the stolen \"Heart of Gold\" in the book \"The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "A space ship", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133894c", "question": "Who created the \"Dilbert\" comic strip?", "answer": "Scott Adams", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a800", "question": "What is the capital of Denmark?", "answer": "Copenhagen", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe9377e6bd93ce3a4e5f66e", "question": "Dendrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Trees", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390e6", "question": "What year was writer Arthur C. Clarke born?", "answer": "1917", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133999a", "question": "On what street do TV's \"Desperate Housewives\" live?", "answer": "Wisteria Lane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c32a", "question": "What part of the eye gives it color?", "answer": "The Iris", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff0b25fe662d71a53650fd7", "question": "Botticelli's \"Birth of Venus\" features a goddess floating in the ocean on what?", "answer": "Seashell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b34e", "question": "What was the nickname of the son of Cleopatra and Julius Caesar?", "answer": "Caesarion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c902fbde8045e48466e6", "question": "Which farm animal sleeps standing up?", "answer": "Horses are the only farm animal that can sleep standing up, and it's due to the unique way their legs are structured.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6af", "question": "What do climbers rub on their hands for extra grip?", "answer": "Chalk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339450", "question": "How did the children die in the 2001 movie \"The Others\"?", "answer": "Suffocation", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c850", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the alveoli?", "answer": "The lungs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339445", "question": "What was the name of Tom Hanks' character in the movie \"Cast Away\"?", "answer": "Chuck Noland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a37", "question": "Which French term literally means \"Fat Tuesday\"?", "answer": "Mardi Gras", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4edf406d333868d34d771", "question": "The musical score for Hitchcock's \"Psycho\" uses which instrument exclusively?", "answer": "Stringed instruments", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1cb", "question": "Which group had a hit with the song \"Back for Good\" in 1995?", "answer": "Take That", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6014c4e7fbde8045e48466a4", "question": "Approximately how many snow crystals fall each winter?", "answer": "One septillion -- That's a trillion trillion, or a one with 24 zeroes behind it. Scientists insist no two flakes are the same.", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a1a", "question": "What kind of creature is Mrs. Tiggy-Winkle in a book by Beatrix Potter?", "answer": "Hedgehog", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b4d8", "question": "Who was said to float like a butterfly and sting like a bee?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4b4549076251badbeac1", "question": "Who was the first female U.S. Attorney General?", "answer": "Janet Reno -- She served as the attorney general for President Bill Clinton's entire presidency.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2d3", "question": "What military legend was nicknamed \"The G.I. General\"?", "answer": "Omar Bradley", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb2ed7e83c707845b2115", "question": "\"Sonar\" stands for what?", "answer": "Sound Navigation And Ranging", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c81e", "question": "What kind of cool star will our Sun become in approximately 5 billion years?", "answer": "A red giant", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af1f", "question": "What everyday item did John Walker invent?", "answer": "Friction matches", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d66", "question": "What is the subtitle of J.R.R. Tolkien's \"The Hobbit\"?", "answer": "There and Back Again", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a662", "question": "What region was explored by Vitus Bering?", "answer": "Arctic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b462", "question": "When did boxer John L. Sullivan die?", "answer": "1918", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febba037e83c707845b2142", "question": "What is the object that opposing players must destroy in order to win at \"League of Legends\"?", "answer": "Nexus", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339567", "question": "What year saw the release of the made-for-TV classic, Frosty the Snowman?", "answer": "1969", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a95", "question": "In ancient Greece, what river did the souls of dead people have to cross?", "answer": "Styx", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133924f", "question": "What movie's first batch of soap is made out of fat from liposuction clinics?", "answer": "Fight Club's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6b7", "question": "The Columbia River flows into what body of water?", "answer": "Pacific Ocean", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5937ed1e08d98002fdd633c4", "question": "The 1976 Summer Olympics were held in which city?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391f4", "question": "In the Disney movie \"Robin Hood\", what animals play Robin Hood and Maid Marian?", "answer": "Foxes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b964", "question": "How many sheets of paper are there in a quire?", "answer": "25", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e0", "question": "Who took Oliver Twist into his home even though he had been accused of picking his pockets?", "answer": "Mr. Brownlow", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aafa", "question": "Which country borders Chad to the north?", "answer": "Libya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4f2", "question": "What word is used in Hawaii as both a greeting and a farewell?", "answer": "Aloha", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ee7", "question": "How many bottles unexpectedly appear in the last verse of Police song \"Message in a Bottle\"?", "answer": "A hundred billion", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cefc2c3948005ec986edceb", "question": "What season did The Simpsons enter in 2018?", "answer": "30", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58f5661133a95c66dc4fe75e", "question": "Which British opera festival was started in 1934?", "answer": "Glyndebourne", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad18", "question": "Which female appeared on the 1999 US dollar coin?", "answer": "Susan B. Anthony", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f23", "question": "Which Old Master signed his paintings with his full Cretan name, Dom\u00e9nikos Theotok\u00f3poulos?", "answer": "El Greco", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab0a2dbaab681b09292165", "question": "Who won the first season of American Idol?", "answer": "Kelly Clarkson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015fb05fe83fe1f2a824c38", "question": "What are the earliest-known Christmas tree decorations?", "answer": "Apples", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ffcfd749dc5ec6cd98a8324", "question": "What famous literary character offers this sage advice: \"Neither a borrower nor a lender be\"?", "answer": "Polonius (In\u00a0\"Hamlet\"\u00a0(Act I, Scene III),\u00a0he offers the sage advice to his son Laertes who is about to leave home.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399c3", "question": "What late 19\u00ad60's pop singer was backed by a group called the Union Gap?", "answer": "Gary Puckett", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcc1", "question": "What is divided by the Cassini Division?", "answer": "Saturn's rings", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b824", "question": "What do Mc and Mac mean when used in surnames?", "answer": "Son of", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feddc076ce05a3942286d97", "question": "What inspired the Grinch\u2019s green color?", "answer": "An ugly car", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af73", "question": "What dam was built during the 1930s, creating Lake Mead?", "answer": "Hoover Dam", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe1ecd7145fb29466707389", "question": "Where did the first Dunkin' Donuts open?", "answer": "Quincy, Massachusetts", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339f24", "question": "What actor did Michael J. Fox replace as Marty McFly in \"Back to the Future\"?", "answer": "Eric Stolz", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d0d", "question": "What movie's first sequel featured the subtitle \"The Quickening\"?", "answer": "Highlander", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd32", "question": "What soccer team won the Premier League in 2004?", "answer": "Arsenal FC", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6bb", "question": "Mariner 9 was the first spacecraft to orbit what other planet?", "answer": "Mars", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fec8aeaec223966ae8f8834", "question": "Fun-loving NBA personality Shaquille O'Neal is actually a doctor. In what field did he earn a doctorate?", "answer": "Education", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a92a", "question": "Where is the Golf Hall of Fame located?", "answer": "St. Augustine, Florida", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b0c", "question": "What was the name of the shipwrecked boat on \"Gilligan's Island\"?", "answer": "S.S. Minnow", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe6a57220565ad31a57c7cc", "question": "In which ancient culture were turkeys believed to be gods?", "answer": "Maya", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b916", "question": "What 2 letters in scrabble have the highest point value?", "answer": "Q and Z", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58b8d5412b42d4a3561a9f00", "question": "In the comic book series \"Strangers in Paradise\", what is the name of Francine\u2019s daughter?", "answer": "Jenny", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a02a", "question": "In the TV show \"Family Guy\", Franz Gutentag was once what?", "answer": "A Nazi war criminal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c1b", "question": "SpongeBob SquarePants lives in a house shaped like what?", "answer": "Pineapple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339dd3", "question": "At age 17, who played the title schoolgirl in \"The Bachelor and the Bobby-Soxer\"?", "answer": "Shirley Temple", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d95", "question": "What TV character had great success with his recipe for Chocolate Salty Balls?", "answer": "Chef", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59008f72cf842fa4c4ba96bb", "question": "The name of which disease comes from Medieval Italian meaning \"bad air\"?", "answer": "Malaria", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b367", "question": "Who married Prince Albert of Saxe-Coburg and Gotha?", "answer": "Queen Victoria", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d6e", "question": "What classic novel's subtitle is \"A Tale of the Christ\"?", "answer": "Ben-Hur", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133927b", "question": "Name the jury members in the order they were eliminated in season 14 of the TV show \"Big Brother\"?", "answer": "Ashley, Britney, Frank, Joe, Jen, Shane, Danielle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133933a", "question": "Who is Charlie's nephew on the TV show \"Two and a Half Men\"?", "answer": "Jake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae56", "question": "During the 1920s, gangster Al Capone ruled over what city?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339244", "question": "What movie was hyped: \"Girls like me don't make invitations like this to just anyone\"?", "answer": "Pulp Fiction", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601214f563c99d48cd169ae4", "question": "Which researcher corrected Einstein's theory of a static universe?", "answer": "Edwin Hubble -- He concluded that the universe is actually expanding, something Einstein would admit was his own blunder.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a69", "question": "For what 1997 film did Kim Basinger win a Best Supporting Actress Oscar?", "answer": "L.A. Confidential", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad77", "question": "Who was the first person to fly solo across the Atlantic ocean?", "answer": "Charles Lindbergh", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9b1", "question": "Kalium is the Latin name for which element?", "answer": "Potassium", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0a0", "question": "In what decade was the voting age in the US lowered to 18?", "answer": "1970's", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7d037877e98cb97778a5d", "question": "Louisville, Kentucky sits on what river?", "answer": "Ohio", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c7d9", "question": "On what namesake Asian island were the first Homo erectus fossils found?", "answer": "Java", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab4a", "question": "What countries share a land border with Somalia?", "answer": "Ethiopia, Djibouti and Kenya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6a2c56c0f9723ab15cb46", "question": "Which volcano had the most powerful eruption of the 20th century?", "answer": "Novarupta volcano", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b22f", "question": "In 1641, who married Mary Stuart, the daughter of England's King Charles I?", "answer": "William of Orange", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe0e3c0fcbed638185eaa25", "question": "Where did Starbucks open their first location outside of North America?", "answer": "Tokyo", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d0", "question": "Who was Martina Navratilova's usual ladies doubles partner in the 1980's?\u00a0", "answer": "Pam Shriver\u00a0", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338952", "question": "What kind of creatures are Nag and Nagaina who plan to kill Rikki-Tikki-Tavi in \"The Jungle Book\"?", "answer": "Cobras", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05c", "question": "What 2005 movie's tagline is \"The longer you wait, the harder it gets\"?", "answer": "The 40 Year Old Virgin", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b119", "question": "What Spanish explorer is credited with discovering the Pacific Ocean?", "answer": "Balboa", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bbaf", "question": "In karate, what color belt is earned just before black?", "answer": "Brown", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b84f", "question": "What physical fitness practice is named for the Sanskrit word for \"union\"?", "answer": "Yoga", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fbae4d50738315b1fb74e20", "question": "What franchise team is the oldest in professional football history in the United States?", "answer": "Arizona Cardinals", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c676", "question": "What is the largest member of the deer family living in the US?", "answer": "The moose", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133969f", "question": "Who is Brian mistaken for in the 1979 movie \"Life of Brian\"?", "answer": "The Messiah", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a8ed", "question": "Thimpu is the capital of what tiny kingdom?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe4ea3606d333868d34d75a", "question": "In what year did Nazi Germany open its first concentration camp?", "answer": "1933", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3ec", "question": "Which war was ended by the \"Peace of Westphalia\"?", "answer": "Thirty Year's War", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea784dff048f679a45abd7", "question": "What word describes a material which maintains a magnetic field after an external field is removed?", "answer": "Ferromagnetic", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b783", "question": "Cyanide is often said to have the bitter aroma of what?", "answer": "Almonds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af45", "question": "What was the first American space station to be launched into space?", "answer": "Skylab", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6014c7cffbde8045e48466c8", "question": "Masses are to Newton's Gravitational Law as charges are to what?", "answer": "Coulomb's Law", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd9691d23c87fd04dd15e06", "question": "Christopher Jones was the captain of what famous ship?", "answer": "The Mayflower", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a161", "question": "Arnold Schwarzenegger is a father trying to get the must have Christmas toy in which 1996 film?", "answer": "Jingle All The Way\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b491", "question": "Which country hosted the first Olympic Games in 1896?", "answer": "Greece", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a755", "question": "The Wyandotte Cave is located in which US state?", "answer": "Indiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea7a41ff048f679a45abe9", "question": "Which constellation are the stars Castor and Pollux in?", "answer": "Gemini", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4b6b006d333868d34d6f3", "question": "In 1908, what three letters became recognized as the universal distress signal?", "answer": "SOS", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339357", "question": "Which Jackson family member had a role in the TV show \"Good Times\"?", "answer": "Janet Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb47", "question": "Within 3 years, either way, in what year did Lou Gehrig deliver his famous farewell speech at Yankee Stadium?", "answer": "1939", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb00665ff7d326b622a5f", "question": "What country's entire population was condemned to death by the Spanish Inquisition?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7664eeec85e375820b27e", "question": "Which mountain range separates Siberia from the Gobi Desert?", "answer": "Altai Mountains", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad15", "question": "Who is the founder of Carthage?", "answer": "Dido", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7b3", "question": "Edam cheese originated in which country?", "answer": "The Netherlands", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6d6", "question": "What city is located across the Columbia River from the city of Vancouver?", "answer": "Portland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f1", "question": "Who made his directorial debut with the 1966 movie \"Who's Afraid of Virginia Woolf\"?", "answer": "Mike Nichols", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5a4a951261d1b4d384d5d674", "question": "In which field of science is the origin of the universe studied?", "answer": "Cosmology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fd6a6fe6c0f9723ab15cb59", "question": "What does \"A.D.\" stand for, in reference to dates?", "answer": "Anno Domini", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea455dff048f679a45ab93", "question": "What South American mammal resembles a small llama?", "answer": "Alpaca", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76782eec85e375820b291", "question": "Which country's national drink is sugarcane juice?", "answer": "Pakistan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339774", "question": "Which company created the Oscar-winning film Finding Nemo?", "answer": "Pixar Animation Studios", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab04", "question": "Mount Vernon is located in which US state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58b3706e1c3f17ccc40c8e14", "question": "What special room was used by patrons who did not want to be seen enjoying a pint in the pub?", "answer": "Snugs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab38", "question": "Which ocean is Cook Islands located in?", "answer": "Pacific", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd668d1a5bfecdd737e0873", "question": "What was the name of the Beatles' first studio album?", "answer": "Cargo House", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdd3eec223966ae8f8902", "question": "Who is the godmother of Kurt Cobain and Courtney Love's kid Francis Bean?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5feba93e7e83c707845b20d4", "question": "What is suspended from the ceiling of the American Natural History Museum?", "answer": "Blue whale", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c74c", "question": "What is the name for the tiny blood vessels that branch off from arteries and veins?", "answer": "Capillaries", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c953", "question": "What is the meaning of the name of the constellation Draco?", "answer": "Dragon", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fed2bb1ec223966ae8f8910", "question": "Who did Nicolas Cage marry in 2002?", "answer": "Lisa Marie Presley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fbd", "question": "What Hollywood legend made his screen debut in 1961's \"Splendor in the Grass\"?", "answer": "Warren Beatty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb35b0d2627b8fe95581bea", "question": "What YouTube Red TV series is based on \"The Karate Kid\" films and stars Ralph Macchio and William Zabka,", "answer": "Cobra Kai", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a226", "question": "In whose memory did Puff Daddy record the song \"I'll Be Missing You\" in 1997?", "answer": "The Notorious B.I.G.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acf6", "question": "Which was the first city to be devastated by the dropping of an atomic bomb?", "answer": "Hiroshima", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59ae94c7574a5ce6b56b824c", "question": "The cobnut is the fruit of what tree?", "answer": "Hazel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad5a", "question": "What president delivered his \"Fourteen Points\" speech in Congress in 1918?", "answer": "Woodrow Wilson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ab1b1ad4fda37788a9a1db3", "question": "Which author wrote \"The Regeneration\" trilogy?", "answer": "Pat Barker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fcc1c5bc97eb73f6a51a273", "question": "What is the longest mountain range on land?", "answer": "The Andes", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84f", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the bronchi?", "answer": "The lungs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad3c", "question": "Who founded the John Birch Society?", "answer": "Robert Welch", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393e0", "question": "What magazine introduced a paper doll named Betsy in 1951?", "answer": "McCall's", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5ff36ce05a3942286e48", "question": "In what movie did Schwartz \"triple-dog-dare\" Flick to stick his tongue on a flagpole?", "answer": "\"A Christmas Story\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395a6", "question": "What are Robin Williams and Nathan Lane pretending to be in the 1996 movie \"The Birdcage\"?", "answer": "Straight", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339218", "question": "What is the theme song of the TV show \"Friends\" called?", "answer": "I'll Be There for You by The Rembrandts", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffe4bf747818f5674af01b5", "question": "For which art form is the Carl Alan Awards given?", "answer": "Dance (Named for Carl Heimann and Alan Fairley,\u00a0awards honor freestyle dance, theatre dance, ballroom, Latin and sequence dance.)", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59071bde3745b36be73039c5", "question": "Who is Tony Chu\u2019s partner in the comic series \"Chew\"?", "answer": "John Colby", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe9f0bdff048f679a45aaa5", "question": "Tachophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Speed", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fc2f74ccee580c7f8fd1e5e", "question": "In underwater diving, what does SCUBA stand for?", "answer": "Self-Contained Underwater Breathing Apparatus", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffa582dc73aa70ea0b70b39", "question": "Which U.S. state has the motto \"Ad astra per aspera\" meaning \"to the stars through difficulties\"?", "answer": "Kansas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be84", "question": "On what Caribbean island did Natalee Holloway disappear in 2005?", "answer": "Aruba", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be9e", "question": "What animal shape are the chocolate pieces in Ben & Jerry's flavor \"Vermonty Python\"?", "answer": "Cows", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5bfdff78b668d7dfe168b5b8", "question": "In Greek mythology, who was Jason's wife?", "answer": "Medea", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5971e13f89261e916c8e09b3", "question": "What alien species is affected by the Genophage in the Mass Effect Series?", "answer": "Krogan", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a223", "question": "Who sang the song \"I'll Be Missing You\" in 1997?", "answer": "Puff Daddy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b942", "question": "What are spit in the annual contest in Paul's Valley, Oklahoma?", "answer": "Watermelon seeds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fef5cbe6ce05a3942286e25", "question": "What is the name of the disembodied hand in \"The Addams Family\"?", "answer": "Thing", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a17", "question": "Which composer of the \"Rite of Spring\" was still alive to see his music used in Disney's \"Fantasia\"?", "answer": "Igor Stravinsky", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe6a1cc20565ad31a57c7a7", "question": "The authors of the Federalist Papers used which pseudonym?", "answer": "Publius", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339612", "question": "In which movie does Woody Allen awaken 200 years in the future?", "answer": "Sleeper", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca3d", "question": "Which element appears ninth on the periodic table?", "answer": "Fluorine", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133976c", "question": "What Will Ferrell movie is about three gun men who start a fraternity and re-live their college years?", "answer": "Old School", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b225", "question": "In which city was American actor Bob Crane murdered?", "answer": "Scottsdale, Arizona", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd2d2db2596a59cbdfbd394", "question": "The Iguazu Falls lie on the border of Brazil and which country?", "answer": "Argentina", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59decff3ea2747c8aff16d22", "question": "Illyngophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Veritgo", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c01f", "question": "What did James Ritty invent in 1879?", "answer": "Cash register", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a75f", "question": "How many countries border Chile?", "answer": "3", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ffb5ce75dad637d903c8820", "question": "What country is nicknamed \"the land of a thousand lakes\"?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7f4", "question": "What is the Bicycle brand famous for making?", "answer": "Playing cards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ef", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows\" what does the acronym RAB stand for?", "answer": "Regulus A. Black", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea48c0ff048f679a45abb3", "question": "Which electronic component can be classified as NPN or PNP?", "answer": "Transistor", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bd9", "question": "According to mythology, what was the food of the gods?", "answer": "Ambrosia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5b69920de762b54eb9be941f", "question": "Who released the album \"The 20/20 Experience\" in 2013?", "answer": "Justin Timberlake", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd3d", "question": "What were the first modern Olympic pole vaulters' poles made of?", "answer": "Bamboo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133beea", "question": "Electric, Perse and smalt are shades of which color?", "answer": "Blue", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a150", "question": "What did Dorothy's house land on in \"The Wizard of Oz\"?", "answer": "The Wicked Witch of the East", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5a7", "question": "In which state was the first Wal-Mart store opened?", "answer": "Arkansas", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b95a", "question": "The surrealist poet Leon-Paul Fargue honored which popular French product with the title \"les pieds de Dieu\"?", "answer": "Cheese", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac12", "question": "The country Comoros is part of which continent?", "answer": "Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6015ddc1fe83fe1f2a824b62", "question": "What color was long considered the color of royalty?", "answer": "Purple", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5feb34897e83c707845b20cb", "question": "The \"Eddie Murphy Rule\" banned certain kinds of insider trading in commodities markets. It was inspired by Murphy\u2019s role in what film?", "answer": "Trading Places", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b75d", "question": "What was the name of Underdog's girlfriend?", "answer": "Polly", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394f0", "question": "What was the name of the character portrayed by Angela Lansbury in \"Murder, She Wrote\"?", "answer": "Jessica Fletcher", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a070", "question": "Which epic film was based on a novel by Lew Wallace?", "answer": "Ben Hur", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4ce", "question": "What European art museum has a glass pyramid in its courtyard?", "answer": "The Louvre", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392fd", "question": "In the movie \"The Karate Kid\", what is the name of Daniel's master?", "answer": "Mr. Miyagi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b889", "question": "In what competition could you see a double axel and a mohawk turn?", "answer": "Figure skating", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe73df7eec85e375820b26f", "question": "How many countries border on the Alps?", "answer": "Eight", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c55", "question": "What year saw the release of Whitney Houston's self-titled debut album?", "answer": "1985", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca48", "question": "What is an Aasvogel?", "answer": "A vulture", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7aa", "question": "Who created the Tabasco sauce?", "answer": "Edmund McIlhenny", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3e5e44f0f6af5b06664b", "question": "In mathematics, which prefix refers to 10 to the power of 18?", "answer": "Exa", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a597", "question": "What do folks from Louisiana and Mississippi call sluggish creeks and marshy lakes?", "answer": "Bayous", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b070", "question": "Who the first American World Chess Champion?", "answer": "Bobby Fisher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b4eb01dd7bf43be5e7ca", "question": "What is the only US state with an official jelly?", "answer": "Louisiana", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338ba6", "question": "What famous baseball poem was written by Ernest Lawrence Thayer?", "answer": "Casey at the Bat", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a47e", "question": "What is the capital of Vermont?", "answer": "Montpelier", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948d", "question": "What did Seymour give to Jake as a birthday present in the movie \"One Hour Photo\"?", "answer": "A camera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa39bfc73aa70ea0b70adb", "question": "In which country did the Mambo dance originate?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b10", "question": "Other than boxing, what does Maggie Fitzgerald do for a living in \"Million Dollar Baby\"?", "answer": "She is a waitress", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5941281cbab1e6f9796f1b5a", "question": "In what sport with animals do you find \"coursing\"?", "answer": "Greyhound racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59cdb6b865ff7d326b622a99", "question": "What US city is named after Saint Francis of Assisi?", "answer": "San Francisco", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d2", "question": "In which comic book did Batman make his first appearance?", "answer": "Detective Comics", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fde4ca2c6c6b019850c9a7d", "question": "How long did biblical Noah live after the flood?", "answer": "350 years", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbe696ce05a3942286eef", "question": "Who recorded the song, \"I Heard a Rumour\"?", "answer": "Bananarama", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b420", "question": "Who was the first Chancellor of West Germany?", "answer": "Konrad Adenauer", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a76b", "question": "What desert gets its name from the Arabic word meaning \"desert\"?", "answer": "Sahara", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b3232dabf195a31e15d7394", "question": "What year was Jodie Foster's directorial debut film, \"Little Man Tate\", released?", "answer": "1991", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b660", "question": "What US auto maker produced a car called the Cirrus?", "answer": "Chrysler", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5a5", "question": "What US city is known as the \"birthplace of jazz\"?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59067b3eff9c0647b50a8062", "question": "With what global issue does the 2016 Paris Agreement deal with?", "answer": "Climate change", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d92", "question": "What famous rapper's real name is Artis Ivey?", "answer": "Coolio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b72b", "question": "How do Japanese children refer to Santa Claus?", "answer": "Santa no ojisan or Uncle Santa", "category": "general"}, {"id": "595642b5803c1f1ebcc4a02d", "question": "A chameleon\u2019s tongue is up to twice the length of its what?", "answer": "Body", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2a3", "question": "Who was made a general in 1935, when he was selected to create the Nazi Luftwaffe?", "answer": "Hermann Goering", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a470", "question": "What is the capital of Mali?", "answer": "Bamako", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f5662b33a95c66dc4fe760", "question": "Mentu is the Egyptian god of what?", "answer": "War", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a28", "question": "What car model gave its name to an alien in \"The Hitchhiker's Guide to the Galaxy\"?", "answer": "Ford Prefect", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a54e", "question": "Which state is nicknamed the \"Mount Rushmore State\"?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6e6", "question": "What two states share a border with Florida?", "answer": "Alabama and Georgia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c5ea", "question": "What type of snake is a Sidewinder?", "answer": "Rattlesnake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b24d", "question": "What civilization lived by the Code of Hammurabi?", "answer": "The Babylonians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fedda536ce05a3942286d84", "question": "Brothers Barry, Robin and Maurice Gibb formed which successful pop group in the late 1950's?", "answer": "Bee Gees", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd9721223c87fd04dd15e50", "question": "Serial killer Rodney Alcala appeared on what 1970s show?", "answer": "\"The Dating Game\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399f4", "question": "What was the name of Archie\u2019s wife on the TV show \"All in the Family\"?", "answer": "Edith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd6a5ec223966ae8f88d5", "question": "In \"The Godfather\" Clemenza says to leave the gun, and take the what?", "answer": "The cannoli", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd66261a5bfecdd737e0844", "question": "How far from shore do international waters start?", "answer": "200 nautical miles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b459", "question": "Herodotus is commonly referred to as what?", "answer": "The Father of History", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c5d", "question": "What was the first full feature film directed by George Lucas?", "answer": "THX 1138", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bea1", "question": "What city's Hotel Adlon was the site of Michael Jackson's 2002 baby dangling?", "answer": "Berlin's", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339325", "question": "In the movie \"Monsters Inc.\", what are the monsters most scared of?", "answer": "Children", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8afb901dd7bf43be5e78a", "question": "What is the term for a word that is spelled the same forwards and backwards?", "answer": "Palindrome", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc3a", "question": "Prior to getting married, Kate Middleton worked as assistant accessory buyer at what clothing chain?", "answer": "Jigsaw", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b511", "question": "How many days were there in 2004?", "answer": "366", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a923", "question": "What country was the birthplace of architects Alvar Aalto and Eero Saarinen?", "answer": "Finland", "category": "geography"}]